

### **Contact**

**Phone** 97916 94834

#### **Email**

rameshkannan000078@gamil.com

#### **Address**

1964 C3, Aasai Nagar, Lenavillaku,pilivalam (po), Pudukottai - 622507

# **Expertise**

HTML5,CSS,C

JAVASCRIPT, NODEJS

MERN STACK, REACTJS, REDUX

MYSQL, MSSQL, SQL

Flutter, BLOC PATTERN

PYTHON, OPENCV, AUTOMATION

JAVA, SPRING BOOT

SELENIUM TESTING

DATA STRUCTURES AND ALGORITHMS

# Language

Tamil

English

Spanish

French

# Ramesh Kannan S

# Full Stack Developer

I am a Full Stack Developer on websites and mobile applications, with 2+ years of part-time work experience in the development domain. My objective is to help companies application that will be more secure and sustainable and will be able to work for years. It is not only sustainable, but it is also able to meet the needs of clients all around the world.

I am looking forward to working in an organisation where I can contribute my creative methodologies and out-of-the-box thinking and be a team player. I have good experience in problem-solving and project development. I am always ready to support and mentor people in the best way I can.

# **Experience**

O July 2022 -

Free Lancer

### **Spring Boot Developer**

Creating java based spring boot apllication for API. I worked prodominently towards the spring boot for backend development and also tested using selenium

Dec 2021 - April 2022

Lumiere De Lucolie

### Flutter Developer

Create a full stack mobile application using flutter android and also worked with api in php. The backend with mysql database. Learned the pattern for developing a business based solutions. More customized with my colleagues.

July 2021 - Aug 2021

Appro Labs

### **Marketing Content Manager**

Contributed some of ideas for digital marketing campaigns. Worked with some of blogs creating and made email marketing. I have learned some of SEO techniques.

June 2022 - Aug 2022

Mount Zion College Of Engineering And Technology

#### **Software Developer**

create some of applications like Digital Library website using Reactjs, Nodejs, Mssql and Expressjs. By creating a full stack web application which is more userfriendly and efficient. Made an canteen management system for students to purchase the food product from college canteen using vb .net and mssql database.

### Personal Details •

Nationality: Indian

Age: 20

Date of Birth: 30-01-2002

Gender: Male

Marital status: single Passport: Available

### Certification

Basics of Python - HackerRank

Web Application - Free Code Camp

Basics of SQL - Hackerrank

Python Automation - Coursera

Python Data Analytics - Coursera

Smart India Hackathon 2022

# **Training**

Python Using Opencv UDEMY, 2021

Artificial Intelligence ACCENTURE, 2021

BootCamp for AI,MI &DA IBM,2021

Aadhaar Hackathon UIDAI, 2021

Introduction to cs5 HARVARD UNIVERSITY, 2021

Introduction to cs5 HARVARD UNIVERSITY, 2021

Smart India Hackathon 2022

### Interest

Cooking

Travelling

Learning specific technologies

# **Projects**

July 2022 -

#### **DIRA**

Flutter Mobile Application where people and police can communicate ananymously of TIPOFFS.

### **FAKEID**

Reactjs web Application the place people can verify the people's social media Accounts.

### **OFFICERS NUMBER FINDER**

Mobile application where higher officials can get the nearest official mobile number for any type of Enquiry.

### HOSPITAL HELPER

Mobile application where people can used to identify the cost of hospital bills, bed charges and scans etc...

### **EMOTION ANALYSER**

python data analytics chat based Emotion analyser

### Education

June 2019 - April 2023

**B.E. Computer Science and Engineering** - **CGPA** (8.02) MOUNT ZION COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

June 2017 - April 2019

**Higher Secondary Education - Computer Science - 72%** ST.MARY'S.HR.SEC.SCHOOL

March.2017

**Secondary School Leaving Certificate - 94%** 

SRI VENKATESWARA MATRICULATION HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL